اَعُوْذُ بِاللهِ مِنَّ الشِّيْطَانِ الرَّجِيْمِ۝
بِسْمِ اللهِ الرَّحْمَانِ الرَّحِيْمَ۝
اَلْحَمْدُ لله وَالصَّلَاةُ وَالسَّلَامُ عَلى سَيِّدِنَا محمد وَعَلَى اَلِهِ وَصَحْبِهِ وَسَلِّمْ
14, Zaat-Ur-Riqa(ذات الرقاع),
it occurred in Jamada Al-Oula(جمادى ألأولى) Fourth of Hijrah(هجرة).
It was named Zaat-Ur-Riqa(ذات الرقاع), which means the Battle of the rags.
Why it was called that, why it was given that name?
Because because the shoes of the Muslims were tearing apart
and their feet were bleeding so they ended up wrapping pieces of their clothes over their feet.
Rasool Allah ﷺ attacked the land of Najd(نجد) but no fighting occurred.
15, the minor battle of Badr(بدر) it happened in Sha'ban(شعبان) year four.
Rasool Allah ﷺ went to Badr(بدر) to meet Abu Sufiyan(أبوسُفيان) and Quraish(قُرَيْشْ) at an appointed time.
He went with 1500 fighters.
Abu Sufiyan(أبوسُفيان) made it halfway but then decided to go back to Makkah.
Number 16, Domat-Ul-Jandal(دومة الجندل),
Domat-Ul-Jandal(دومة الجندل), is at the extreme southern tip of Ash-Sham(ألشَّام).
Domat-Ul-Jandal(دومة الجندل), is the borders between the Arabian Peninsula and Ash-Sham(ألشَّام).
It is a town surrounded by an impregnable wall.
Rasool Allah ﷺ attacked it, when he heard that the non believers are gathering an army to invade Madina.
So Rasool Allah ﷺ would not wait for an enemy to come to him, he would go out and meet them.
He heard that they're mobilizing an army he went out all the way to Ash-Sham(ألشَّام).
He marched towards them, in an army of 1000,
he would move at night and hide during the day.
When the enemy heard of his move.
They feared him and ended up dispersing.
So when Rasool Allah ﷺ arrived in their territory, none of them came out to fight.
He attacked their shepherds and confiscated some of their cattle
and sent out detachments to different areas and then returned.
Number 17, Al-Khandaq(ألخندق),
the Battle of the Trench occurred in Shawal(شوال), fifth of Hijrah(هجرة).
Quraish(قُرَيْشْ) came headed by Abu Sufiyan(أبوسُفيان),
Banu Fuzara(بنوفزارة) were headed by Oyena Bin Hasan(عيينة بن حصن),
Bano Murrah(بنومرَّة) headed by Haris Bin Aof(حارث بن عوف),
In addition to Ghatafan(غطافان) and Ash'jah(أشجاع),
and they all converged on Madina in an army of 5000.
Allah O Alam(ألله أعلم),
this number is underestimate, should be more than 5000.
When Rasool Allah ﷺ receive news of the armies.
He consulted with the Sahabah(صحابه),
and that is one Salman Farsi(سلمان فارسي) suggested digging the trench, which was a novel idea to Arab warfare.
The trench was completed with a little over 10 days, the Muslims were 3000.
So this was a coalition that attacked Madina.
It was made up of Quraish(قريش), Ghatafan(غطافان), Ash'jah(أشجاع) some other tribes,
alongside, Al-Munafiqoon(ألمنافقون) from within Madina.
And later on, Banu Quraidha(بنوقريظه).
Rasool Allah ﷺ heard the news of this advance, and the army was large, the army of the Kuffar(كفار).
So, Salman Farsi(سلمان فارسي) suggested this idea, he said:
This is something that we do in Persia, so this was an imported idea.
This was an idea that was not known to the Arabs.
Salman Farsi(سلمان فارسي) said: Let's dig a trench.
The Trench was dug, north of Madina.
Even though Makkah is towards the south, Why was it to the north of Madina.?
Because Madina had natural defenses from the three other sides,
from the eastern and the west it was defended by a volcanic rocky track, very sharp rocks.
It's very difficult for an army to march through,
and then you have the palm groves, towards the south,
which also makes it very difficult for a large army.
So the trench was built, was dug towards the north of Madina,
an interesting event occurred,
the Sahabah رضي الله عنهم came across this boulder that refused to move out of their way.
They tried to break it, but it would end up breaking their axes.
So they went to Rasool Allah ﷺ and they complained to him.
Rasool Allah ﷺ went there he asked for an axe they give it to him he said:
Allah o Akbar(ألله أكبر) and he struck the Boulder,
and it cracked and the spark of light came out of it.
Rasool Allah ﷺ made Takbir(تكبير).
And then he did it again, it's cracked a second time and light came out,
the third time he hit it, it just broke into pieces.
And Rasool Allah ﷺ made Takbir(تكبير).
Sahabah رضي الله عنهم  said: Why did you make Takbir(تكبير)?
Rasool Allah ﷺ said: Because the first time I saw the palaces of Syria.
And Allah told me that my Ummah(امة) would enter the land of the Romans.
And I made Takbir(تكبير) the second time because Allah showed me the white palaces of Madaen(مدائن), the capital of Persia,
and Allah told me that my nation will enter the land of Persia,
and the third time I said Allah O Akbar(ألله أكبر) because Allah showed me the gates of San'a(صنعاء) in Yemen,
and told me that my nation will enter into Yemen.
When was Rasool Allah ﷺ giving this promise,
you've noticed that the greatest promises to this Ummah(امة)
were delivered to the Ummah(امة) when the Ummah(امة) was at its lowest point.
Because these promises were a test of faith,
Al-Munafiqoon(ألمنافقون) they were laughing so much and mocking at this, they said:
احد على يامن على يخرج لقضاء حاجت
One of us doesn't even feel secure to respond to the call of nature,
and Rasool Allah ﷺ is telling us that we're gonna open Persia and the Roman Empire, and Yemen.
What is he talking about.?
But the believers said:
هذا ما وعدنا الله ورسوله
Believers say: This is what the Allah and His messenger  promised us, it's gonna happen.
Another promise that was given by Rasool Allah ﷺ,
another incident to show you when the promises are given,
when Rasool Ullah and Abu Bakr(ابوبكر) are running away from Makkah, they're on the run
and Quraish(قُرَيْشْ), are pursuing them.
And they place a bounty on the head of Muhammadﷺ One hundred camels.
Suraqah Bin Malik Al-Ashjae(سراقه بن مالك ألأشجاعي) one of the Bedouins, he was sitting among his people he's not from Makkah
but the news is going around that there's ransom on Muhammadﷺ, Dead or Alive.
So somebody came in to the gathering and said:
I've seen two men walking in the desert, they might be Muhammadﷺ and his companions.
Suraqah(سراقه) said:
No, no, no it's not them. I was there, and I saw them.
But then Suraqah(سراقه) sneaked out of that meeting,
he went to his house, called his horse and ran out in pursuit of the two men,
because he thought these might be Muhammad(محمد) and Abu Bakr(ابوبكر), he wanted 100, camels.
So, he's pursuing them,
Abu Bakr(ابوبكر) is looking behind, he is looking behind
and Rasool Allah ﷺ is reciting Qur'an, he's not even looking behind
and Abu Bakr(ابوبكر) is very worried, staring behind.
Rasool Allah ﷺ is walking confidently without looking back.
And then Suraqah(سراقه), when he gets close.
The front feet of his horse sink in the sand, and he falls.
He said: My horse never did this.
He jumps on his horse again and pursues Muhammadﷺ, it happens a second time.
And then the third time it happened he saw a wall of dust in front of him.
So he started asking Muhammadﷺ to give him peace.
He's out to capture Muhammadﷺ and he is now asking Muhammadﷺ to give him peace.
Rasool Allah ﷺ said: I will give you Amaan(أمان),
and then Rasool Allah ﷺ told him:
O Suraqah(سراقه), what about a the day, when you will be wearing the bracelets of Kisra(كسرى).
Now there's only one Kisra(كسرى) in the world.
So, it's very well known who that Kisra(كسرى) is.
But it is such a strange thing to say that Suraqah(سراقه) had to make sure that he heard it right,
he said: Kisra(كسرى)!
Rasool Allah ﷺ said: Yes Kisra Ibn Hurmz(كسرى إبن هرمز),
Kisra(كسرى) the son of Hurmz(هرمز) to make to make it clear.
Obviously Suraqah(سراقه) didn't understand what that meant, and how would I wear the bracelets of Kisra(كسرى).
Now these bracelets apparently were very famous
it's like something that everybody knew was, special bracelets of Kisra(كسرى).
Suraqah(سراقه) somehow he told Muhammadﷺ to write,
Rasool Allah ﷺ gave him Amaan(أمان), gave him Amaan(أمان), gave him peace.
Suraqah(سراقه) said: I wanted on paper.
Allah O Alam(ألله أعلم) how came you would ask such a thing.
He said: Write it for me on paper.
So, Rasool Allah ﷺ told Abu Bakr(ابوبكر) write that down for him.
So, Abu Bakr(ابوبكر) wrote down on this sheet of paper.
That Rasool Allah ﷺ is giving Suraqah Bin Malik(سراقه بن مالك) peace.
When the land of Suraqah(سراقه) was opened,
and they were going to kill Suraqah Bin Malik(سراقه بن مالك), few years years later.
Suraqah Bin Malik(سراقه بن مالك) pulls out that paper and says Muhammad(محمد) has given me peace.
And that saves his life.
He then becomes Muslim Rasool Allah ﷺ passes away, Abu Bakr(ابوبكر) passes away Umar(عُمَر) becomes Khalifah(خليفه)
and Suraqah(سراقه) joins the army that's going to persia.
And they conquer Persia, and the treasures of Kisra(كسرى) are brought back to Madina.
And among the treasure, they found the bracelets of Kisra(كسرى).
Umar Ibn Al-Khattab(عمرابن الخطاب) called Suraqah(سراقه), to stand up on the pulpit,
and to wear the bracelets of Kisra(كسرى) and to tell the Muslims, the story about it.
Suraqah(سراقه), this simple Bedouin is wearing the bracelets of Kisra Ibn Hurmuz(كسرى إبن هرمز).
But that's a promise that was made by Rasool Allah ﷺ when he was on the run.
Its takes a lot of faith to believe in something like that.
So now when the Ummah(امة) is at its low point.
And hopefully we have reached the rock bottom,
In Sha Allah(إنْ شاءالله) there's nothing lower than this.
That we can only go up from there.
Allahعَزَّوَجَلْ has promised this Ummah(امة).
Number one,
تكون فيكم النبوة ما شاء الله أن تكون،
ثم ينزع الله إذاشاء أن ينزعها،
ثم تكون خلافة راشدة فتكون فيكم ما شاء الله أن تكون ثم ينزع الله إذا شاء أن ينزعها،
ثم تكون ملكًا عاضًا فتكون فيكم ما شاء الله أن تكون ثم ينزعها الله إذا شاء الله أن ينزعها، ،
ثم تكون ملكًا جبرية
فيكون فيكم ما شاء الله أن يكون، ثم ينزعها الله إذا شاء أن ينزعها،
ثم تكون خلافة على منهاج النبوة
Rasool Allah ﷺ says it will first start with prophethood,
and will stay for as long as Allah wants and then Allah will take it away.
And then it will be Khilafah Rashida(خِلَافَه راشده), rightly guided,
and it will stay among you as long as Allah wants to stayand then Allah will take it away.
And then it will be kingdom, and will stay with you as long as Allah wants to stay and then Allah takes it away,
and then it will be dictatorship, tyranny.
And it will remain with you as long as Allah wants it to remain and then Allah will take it away.
And then it will be Khilafah(خِلَافَه) on the path of Prophethood.
Right now we're going through that tyrannical dictatorship stage.
And there's only Khilafah(خِلَافَه) after it.
That's the next stage, it's Khilafah(خِلَافَه).
Number two, Rasool Allah ﷺ says:
إنَّ اللَّهَ زَوَى لي الأرْضَ،
فَرَأَيْتُ (مَشارِقَها ومَغارِبَها)،وإنَّ مُلكَ أُمَّتي سيبلُغُ ما زُوِيَ لي مِنها،
Rasool Allah ﷺ says: Allah has shrinked the earth in front of my eyes and showed it to me.
And he told me, that the kingdom of my nation will reach all of it, the entire earth!
Number three Rasool Allah ﷺ says:
سَيَبْلُغن هذا الدين ما بلغ اللَّيل والنَّهار،
بِعِزِّ عَزِيزٍ أو بِذُلِّ ذَليلٍ، ،
عِزًّا يُعِزُّ الله به الإسلام وذُلًّا يُذِلُّ الله به الشِرك
This religion will reach wherever night and day reaches
every corner of earth, where night and day reaches, this religion will reach.
And it will honor some and it will humiliate some.
It will honor the believers and dishonor the disbelievers.
It's gonna happen!
The coalition army laid siege to Madina for over 20 days.
During that time, Nuaim Ibn Masood(نعيم إبن مسعود)
a prominent member of the coalition came to the Messenger of Allah to announce Islam.
Allahعَزَّوَجَلْ says:
وما يعلم جنود ربك إلَّا هو
Only Allah knows His soldiers.
Allahعَزَّوَجَلْ has soldiers in unexpected quarters.
Who would have imagined that in the capital of evil in the world,
in the palace of Firaun(فرعون), the center of the plotting of evil,
that's where Shaytan(شَيْطَانْ) would spend most of his time
because that's where his most loyal soldier is, the Palace of Firaun(فرعون).
Nevertheless, Allahعَزَّوَجَلْ has a soldier inside the palace of Firaun(فرعون).
So when Musa عليه السّلام is picked up by the soldiers and they take him,
فَالتَقَطَهُ آلُ فِرعَونَ
Allahعَزَّوَجَلْ says:
فَالتَقَطَهُ آلُ فِرعَونَ لِيَكونَ لَهُم عَدُوًّا وَحَزَنًا ۗ
إِنَّ فِرعَونَ وَهامانَ وَجُنودَهُما كانوا خاطِئينَ۞
He was picked up by the people of Firaun(فرعون). And Allah says,
لِيَكونَ لَهُم عَدُوًّا وَحَزَنًا ۗ
So, that he would be the demise for them.
As soon as he got into the palace, the soldier of Allah came to him.
The wife of Firaun(فرعون), and she fell in love with Musa(موسى) as soon as, she saw him.
And she said:
قرَّة عين لي ولك
I want him to be,
قرَّة عين
Please my eye and yours.
Firaun(فرعون) said: I don't want him but if you want to have him, take him.
A soldier of Allah inside the palace of Firaun(فرعون),
to nurture and upbring Musa عليه السّلام.
The wind is a soldier of Allah, the thunders are a soldier of Allah, water which is the cause of life,
وجعلنا من الماء كل شيء حي
We have made out of water every living being,
water was a soldier of Allah that destroyed Firaun(فرعون),
a mosquito can be a soldier of Allah it destroyed Namrood(نمرود).
So you don't know where the soldier of Allah is, don't count,
just on what you have because Allahعَزَّوَجَلْ has soldiers around you.
And if you have the Taqwa(تقوى) of Allahعَزَّوَجَلْ, Allah will send the soldiers to you.
You never know what they are.
Subhaan Allah(سُبْحَان الله), the believers would be in very tight situations.
And Allah opens up a door for them, they have never expected before.
Nuaim Ibn Masood(نعيم إبن مسعود) comes to Rasool Allah ﷺ.
This is a man who came out with the coalition to fight against the Muslims,
when he gets there, Allah puts in his heart, the love of Islam.
It seems to be the wrong timing.
But Allahعَزَّوَجَلْ is the One, Who controls the hearts.
You are out there to fight against the Muslims and then you want to become Muslim,
how come you didn't become Muslim before,
but this is the Qadar(قَدَر) of Allahعَزَّوَجَلْ.
إِنَّكَ لا تَهدي مَن أَحبَبتَ وَلٰكِنَّ اللَّهَ يَهدي مَن يَشاءُ ۚ
Allahعَزَّوَجَلْ is the One, Who guides.
So he comes to Rasool Allah ﷺ and says I want to become Muslim.
Rasool Allah ﷺ, took the pledge of allegiance from him.
And then Nuaim Ibn Masood(نعيم إبن مسعود) wants to sign up and enlist in the Muslim army.
Rasool Allah ﷺ said:
إنَّما أنت رجل واحد
You are one man.
With us you are just an additional soldier.
ولكن خذل عنا مستطعنا
But go back to them.
And weaken them from within, weaken them from within,
خذل عنا مستطعنا
So Nuaim Ibn Masood(نعيم إبن مسعود), goes back and Rasool Allah ﷺ, this is an important quality of leadership,
you put the right person in the right place, you know what your soldiers are able to do.
You know their skills you study, you study their profile, very well.
So, you know where to put them.
Rasool Allah ﷺ told Nuaim Ibn Masood(نعيم إبن مسعود) with us, you just one soldiers,
you're one man go to them and weaken them from within.
So Nuaim Ibn Masood(نعيم إبن مسعود) goes back.
Nuaim Ibn Masood(نعيم إبن مسعود) had some good networking abilities.
So he went to Banu Quraidha(بنوقريظه).
He was a former friend, it was a friend of Banu Quraidha(بنوقريظه),
a friend of Hawazin(هوازن), a friend of Quraish(قُرَيْشْ), he knew everyone.
He went to Banu Quraidha(بنوقريظه) and he said:
What have you done?
you know Banu Quraidha(بنوقريظه) when the coalition arrived,
out of their foolishness they sided with the coalition, against Muhammadﷺ.
Now for the Muslims, this was the most difficult moment on them.
I think we talked about, how come it was a difficult situation
because they were the only Jewish tribe, who was very close to Rasool Allah ﷺ
because now Banu Nadhir(بنونضير) and Banu Qainqah(بنوقينقاع) left and Khaybar(خَيْبَر) is far away.
So Banu Quraidha(بنوقريظه) they sided with Quraish(قُرَيْشْ).
Nuaim(نعيم) goes to them and says: What have you done.?
These Arabs are gonna, if they find it tough and difficult,
they're gonna leave you, they're gonna go back to their homes.
And you are the ones who are going to suffer the consequences of Muhammadﷺ.
The consequences of what you have done against Muhammadﷺ.
Quraish(قُرَيْشْ) are going to go back to Makkah,
Hawazin(هوازن) are going to go back to their land,
and the tribes of Najd(نجد) are gonna go back to Najd(نجد),
and you're gonna stay here alone, and Rasool Allah ﷺ is gonna come to you.
What have you done?
They said: What do you suggest,
he said: Listen!
To ensure that the people of Quraish(قُرَيْشْ) and the Arabs stay,
you have to take some hostages from them.
And you make it clear that you're not going to fight,
unless you give us these hostages, because these people are going to leave you alone.
So they said: That's a very good idea.
They liked it!
Nuaim Ibn Masood(نعيم إبن مسعود) goes to Quraish(قُرَيْشْ) and to the Arab tribes,
he tells them, how can you trust these Jews.?
How can you trust these people.?
They have regretted breaking their agreement with Muhammadﷺ.
And as a retribution for that, they made the deal with Muhammadﷺ,
that they're gonna hand them over some of your men.
So if the Jews come to ask for any hostages do not give them any.
Because they want to hand them over to Muhammadﷺ as retribution for breaking their promise to him.
Abu Sufiyan(أبوسُفيان) said: We agreed!
Abu Sufiyan(أبوسُفيان) now he is already worried because of what Nuaim(نعيم) said.
So, he sends a letter to the Jews telling them, you attack on Saturday we're gonna attack on Sunday.
The Jews said:
We're not gonna attack, unless you send us some men to ensure
that you're gonna stay until the last moment, and not going to leave us alone.
Abu Sufiyan(أبوسُفيان) said: This is exactly what Nuaim Ibn Masood(نعيم إبن مسعود) said.
The Jews have betrayed their agreement with us.
Abu Sufiyan(أبوسُفيان) said: We're not going to send you anyone.
The Jews said: Aha, this is exactly what Nuaim Ibn Masood(نعيم إبن مسعود) said.
The Arabs are not serious about it and they're gonna walk out, the coalition Broke.
That was the end of the coalition.
One man brought an end to this coalition, One man!
Don't waste your resources.!
If you are just going to be one man in an army.
And you could do a lot more somewhere else.
Make sure that you put yourself in the right place.
And this would go back to what we were saying about,
you know,
using your skills wisely and what Allah has given you here in the West,
take advantage of what Allah has given you here because over there.
You count as one soldier only.
So make sure that you take advantage of the Naem(نعم) that Allahعَزَّوَجَلْ has given you,
it's a business, it's a business with Allah.
You want to capitalize on what Allah has given you, you invest your capital.
If you don't get into an investment of a million dollars and you only have 100,000,
you invest according to the capital you have, this is an investment between you and Allahعَزَّوَجَلْ.
So you want to make sure that you optimize it to the limit and make the most profit that you can make, the maximum.
So use whatever Allah has given you,
optimize it to the maximum, and try to make the best returns.
And every one of you has different abilities, some of you have intellectual abilities.
Some of you have physical abilities, some of you have business abilities.
Some have networking abilities.
Every one of you, Allahعَزَّوَجَلْ has given them something, everyone.
Everyone has something and if Allah has given you that Nema(نعمة).
He wants you to thank him for it.
And the way you thank him for it is to pay your dues.
You owe it to Allahعَزَّوَجَلْ that you have to use what He has given you to serve Him.
And then Allahعَزَّوَجَلْ sent on them, another soldier of his and that was wind.
Very violent wind blew, at night.
The Kuffar(كفار) of Quraish(قُرَيْشْ), they want to cook the wind would drop all of the containers.
They want some warmth, it would extinguish all of their fires.
Rasool Allah ﷺ sent Hudaifa Bin Yaman(حذيفه بن يمان) to go and spy on them.
So Hudaifa(حذيفه) went to spy on them,
and he was sitting around this campfire and everything is just pouring and the fire is going off.
Abu Sufiyan(أبوسُفيان) got tired and he said:
Just let's pack up and leave and they left.
That was the end of the battle Al-Khandaq(ألخندق).
Allahعَزَّوَجَلْ just says,
وَرَدَّ اللَّهُ الَّذينَ كَفَروا بِغَيظِهِم لَم يَنالوا خَيرًا ۚ
وَكَفَى اللَّهُ المُؤمِنينَ القِتالَ ۚ وَكانَ اللَّهُ قَوِيًّا عَزيزًا۞
And Allah repelled those who disbelieved in their rage, not having obtained any good,
and sufficient was Allah for the believers in battle.
And Ever is Allah powerful, and Exalted in Might.
Al-Ahzab(ألأحزاب) Verse 25.
Now, number 18 Banu Quraidha(بنوقريظه), obviously.
Rasool Allah ﷺ he went home, after Quraish(قُرَيْشْ) left,
Rasool Ullah went home, this was a very long siege it took 20 days
the Muslims were very uptight.
They had to guard every corner of Madina.
Financially it was tight, so it was a very exhausting 20 days.
Rasool Allah ﷺ went back home, the Sahabah(صحابه) went back home, and Rasool Ullah taken off his clothes.
Jibreel(جِبْرِيْل) comes and stands at his door, he says: Oh Muhammad(محمد),
Are you laying down your arms, Muhammadﷺ said: Yes!
Jibreel(جِبْرِيْل) said: O Muhammad(محمد), the angels have not laid down their arms yet.
Allah is commanding you to go to the fortresses of Banu Quraidha(بنوقريظه),
and I will go ahead of you, and shake it from beneath them.
Don't lay down your arms yet.
You have to go to the Kuffar(كفار) of Banu Quraidha(بنوقريظه).
So Rasool Allah ﷺ told the Sahabah(صحابه) because of the urgency of it,
Rasool Ullah told the Sahabah(صحابه),
لا يصلي ان احدكم العصر اِلَّا بنوقريظة
Don't pray Asr(عصر) except Banu Quraidha(بنوقريظه).
So the army left.
But the thing is the time of Asr(عصر) arrived when they didn't get there yet.
And they felt that, even if they continue marching,
they would miss the time of Asr(عصر).
So they disputed, some of them said:
Let's pray here, because the time of Asr(عصر) would go out.
The other said: No! Rasool Allah ﷺ said:
You pray Asr(عصر) there even if it's time of Maghrib(مغرب).
So some of them left and some of them stay behind.
Rasool Allah ﷺ when they came back, he approved both of them.
Some people took the Hadith(حديث) literally, some people took it in a figurative sense.
That what Rasool Ullah meant by praying Asr(عصر) there, is that you speed up and approved both interpretations.
So this shows you that differences in the understanding of Hadith(حديث) are possible and acceptable.
Anyway they reach to the fortress of Banu Quraidha(بنوقريظه),
and Jibreel(جِبْرِيْل) is shaking it from under them, not physically, but their hearts are shaking.
Their hearts were shaking.
So Rasool Allah ﷺ gets there.
And after a very short while, Banu Quraidha(بنوقريظه).
They want to surrender but they have a feeling that the consequences are not going to be that good.
So they asked one of their former allies Abu Lubaba(أبولبابة),
who was one of the Al-Ansaar(اَلْاَنْصَار), who used to be their ally before from Al-Aos(ألأوس),
because Banu Quraidha(بنوقريظه) were the allies of Al-Aos(ألأوس),
while Banu Qainqah(بنوقينقاع) and Banu Nadhir(بنونضير) were the allies of Al-Khazraj(ألخزرج).
So Abu Lubaba(أبولبابة) said: I'm not gonna come to you until I get permission from Rasul Ullah.
He goes to Rasool Allah ﷺ, Rasul Ullah told him: I give you permission.
Abu Lubaba(أبولبابة) goes there.
They set out their women and children and they were weeping and crying.
So imagine Abu Lubaba(أبولبابة) going in and all what he sees in front of him, women and children crying,
and they're begging him to do something for them.
Spare our lives, do something for us.
So it was a very emotional thing.
And then they asked Abu Lubaba(أبولبابة).
If we surrender, what do you think Rasul Ullah would do.?
Abu Lubaba(أبولبابة) didn't speak, he pointed to his throat and he did like this, which means you're going to be killed.
Abu Lubaba(أبولبابة) said: By the time I placed my hand down,
I realized that I have betrayed Allah and His Messenger.
I've said something that I wasn't supposed to say.
This was, it's private information.
But the lesson here to learn is that out of human kindness you could have some mercy on the Kuffar(كفار),
so a person needs to be careful and not put themselves into situations where they would compromise in their religion.
Don't want to put yourself in a situation where you would compromise in your religion.
It was very difficult for him to see women and children crying.
And that's when he made this move, which he wasn't supposed to do.
He said: When I left, I knew that, I'm in a very dangerous situation.
So I told myself: I'm not going to face Rasool Allah ﷺ until Allah has mercy on me.
And he goes to the Masjid(مسجد) and tells his wife to tie him to one of the pillars in the Masjid(مسجد).
So Rasool Ullah is waiting for Abu Lubaba(أبولبابة) to come back, he didn't come back.
Rasool Ullah said: How come he is so late.
They said: O Rasool Ullah, this is what happened and he tied himself to pillar in the Masjid(مسجد).
Rasool Allah ﷺ said: If he would have came to me, I would have ask Allah to forgive him.
But if he has, taken this step,
I'm not gonna release him, from that pillar until Allahعَزَّوَجَلْ has At-Toba(التوبة) on him.
So he stays there. For every Salah(صلاة) his wife would come and untie him.
To make Wudhoo(وضؤ) and to pray, and then she would bring him food,
and that carried on for six days, until Allahعَزَّوَجَلْ revealed the Ayah(آية).
Seeking His At-Toba(التوبة).
Back to the issue of the Ghazwa(غزوة).
So Banu Quraidha(بنوقريظه) even though Abu Lubaba(أبولبابة) told them that most likely your throats will be slit.
The fear was just too much.
So they surrendered and they surrendered and Rasool Allah ﷺ told them:
Would you be satisfied, this is before the surrender, when they were negotiating the terms.
Rasool Allah ﷺ said: Would you be happy if I give authority over you to one of your allies, Saad Bin Muadh(سعد بن معاذ).
They said: We agree,
Saad Bin Muadh(سعد بن معاذ) was the head of Al-Aos(ألأوس)
and the Al-Aos(ألأوس) were the allies of Banu Quraidha(بنوقريظه).
So Saad Bin Muadh(سعد بن معاذ) was their ally, they were very happy.
They said: We agree.
Saad Bin Muadh(سعد بن معاذ) was different than Abdullah Bin Obaeye(عبدالله بن اُبَيئ).
Abdullah Bin Obaeye(عبدالله بن اُبَيئ) was bargaining for his people Banu Qainqah(بنوقينقاع), until he set them free.
Saad Bin Muadh(سعد بن معاذ) in the battle of Al-Khandaq(الخندق).
Saad Bin Muadh(سعد بن معاذ) was described as being a tall and big, he was a large man.
Ayesha(عائشه) said:
I ventured out of my house to see what was happening.
So I saw Saad Bin Muadh(سعد بن معاذ) walking in armory that wasn't covering his limbs.
So, his shoulders his arms, his feet, his legs were exposed.
So Ayesha(عائشه) said: I was very worried that he might be hurt,
because he was a very large man, the armory didn't cover his body.
And then Ayesha(عائشه) said: I went into some of the places where the Muslim soldiers were.
So, Umar(عُمَر) saw me and said:
انكي لجري
What are you doing here?
and Ayesha(عائشه) said: He kept on yelling at me, until I felt I want the earth to swallow me.
He said: What are you doing over here.?
Anyway, Saad(سعد), was hit by an arrow, either in his arm or shoulder.
And it was quite a severe injury.
So he made the Dua(دُعَا), he said:
Oh Allah, if there is any fighting left with Quraish(قُرَيْشْ)
then allow me to live, so that I can fight with your messenger.
But if there is no fighting with Quraish(قُرَيْشْ) left,
then let me die, through this injury.
And Oh Allah, don't let me die until you please my eyes with Banu Quraidha(بنوقريظه).
Saad Bin Muadh(سعد بن معاذ) is saying:
If there's any fighting with Quraish(قُرَيْشْ) left, let me live.
Because he was the leader of Al-Ansaar(اَلْاَنْصَار),
and he wanted to make sure that he doesn't die until he has given Rasool Allah ﷺ victory against Quraish(قُرَيْشْ).
That was their agreement.
If the fighting with Quraish(قُرَيْشْ) is over, than O Allah, allow me to die.
And then he wanted his eyes to be pleased with Banu Quraidha(بنوقريظه).
And we'll see what that means.
So, Banu Quraidha(بنوقريظه) now have agreed that whatever Saad(سعد), judges among them, they will accept it.
Saad(سعد) is injured, so they are carrying him on a stretcher and bringing him in to Rasool Allahﷺ
and Saad(سعد) is flanked on both sides by the leaders of Al-Aos(ألأوس).
And they are telling him,
أحسن في موالينا، أحسن في موالينا
Treat our allies well, treat our allies well, treat our allies as well.
Because you know they're seeing what Al-Khazraj(ألخزرج) did.
And there's competition between Al-Aos(ألأوس) and Al-Khazraj(ألخزرج).
Al-Khazraj(ألخزرج) were successful in pleading the clemency of Banu Qainqah(بنوقينقاع) and Banu Nadhir(بنونضير)
both of them were spared.
So Al-Aos(ألأوس), they want the same to happen to their Jewish allies,
And Saad Bin Muadh(سعد بن معاذ) is quiet, and then he responded by saying;
لقد آن لسعد ألا تأخذه في الله لومة لائم
It's about time for Saad(سعد), not to fear the blame of the blamers, in the sake of Allah.
Some of the men just walked away, and went back to their homes and said:
We offer our condolences to Banu Quraidha(بنوقريظه), that's it, they are dead.
So Saad(سعد) is carried on the stretcher and he is brought in.
Saad(سعد) was a leader.
He was a very strong personality and he was a man that had this dignity and presence.
So when he was brought in on the stretcher and everybody was sitting.
Rasool Allah ﷺ said:
قومولسيدكم
Stand up for your leader!
Now this is the first time ever, Rasool Allah ﷺ order somebody to stand up for someone.
Rasool Allah ﷺ in fact, has not allowed the Sahabah(صحابه) to stand up for him.
But when Saad(سعد) was brought in, he said: Stand up!
So, they stood up, and then Saad(سعد) was placed on a stretcher
and the leaders of Banu Quraidha(بنوقريظه) are on one side
and Rasool Allah ﷺ and the Sahabah(صحابه), on the other side,
and Saad(سعد), is in the middle.
So Rasool Allah ﷺ is telling Saad(سعد): Judge among them O Saad(سعد).
Saad(سعد) he looks at Banu Quraidha(بنوقريظه) and he says:
Do you all accept my judgment on you.
They said: Yes!
And then out of respect, Saad Bin Muadh(سعد بن معاذ) does not look towards Rasool Allah ﷺ
but he just points with his hand and says:
And do you accept my judgment.
Because Saad(سعد), he didn't feel it appropriate to look at Rasool Ullah and say:
Do you accept my judgment.
So he said:
وعلى من هاهنا
And the ones here, do you accept my judgment.
Rasool Allah ﷺ said: Yes!
Saad(سعد) said:
فان حكمي فيهم
My judgment among them is that all of their male fighting men should be executed,
and all of their women and children are taken into captivity and enslaved,
and all of their wealth is taken as booty for the Muslims.
Rasool Allah ﷺ said:
لقد حكمت فيهم بحكم الله من فوقه سبع سموات
You have judged, among them by the judgment of Allah from on top seven heavens.
This is the judgment of Allahعَزَّوَجَلْ.
Rasool Allah ﷺ ordered the trench to be dug in the marketplace in Madina.
And then the men of Banu Quraidha(بنوقريظه) are brought in loads of 10
and were executed and the executioner was Ali Ibn Abi Talib(علي ابن ابي طالب)
and when he gets tired then Az-Zubair Bin Awwam(ألزبير بن عوام).
They would execute all of the ones who are above the age of puberty
and the way they would figure that out is they would uncover them
and see if they have grown any pubic hair.
Anyone who has grown pubic hair was executed,
and they would bring them on top of this trench and execute them and throw them in,
execute and throw them in.
Imagine Ali(علي) and Zubair(زبير) executed 700 to 900 Men.
700 to 900 men were executed by Ali Ibn Abi Talib(علي ابن ابي طالب) and Az-Zubair Bin Awwam(ألزبير بن عوام).
And all of their property was taken over.
for Saad Bin Muadh(سعد بن معاذ), Rasool Ullah ordered that a tent to be set for him, in the Masjid(مسجد)
and he be tended to, in the Masjid(مسجد).
And there was another tent close to him, set by some visitors to Madina from Ghaffar(غفار).
They had their tent.
Suddenly, when they were in their tent, they saw this blood streaming into their tent.
They said: What is this?
And they want to see, the injury of Saad(سعد) exploded.
And he was bleeding, and he died.
So Allahعَزَّوَجَلْ has fulfilled his Dua(دُعَا).
He did not die, until his eyes were pleased by the fate of Banu Quraidha(بنوقريظه),
and he died because there was no more fighting with Quraish(قُرَيْشْ).
Al-Khandaq(خندق) was the last battle with Quraish(قُرَيْشْ), there was no fighting after that.
Rasool Allah ﷺ says:
لقد أهتزاز عرش الرحمن لموت سعد إبن معاذ
Rasool Allah ﷺ said: The Throne of Allahعَزَّوَجَلْ shook, when Saad Bin Muadh(سعد بن معاذ) died.
The Throne of Allah, moved when Saad Bin Muadh(سعد بن معاذ) died.
Some of the scholars say: Because the angels loved him so much the angels who're carrying the Throne of Allah,
when they heard the news that Saad(سعد) died.
They moved so the Throne of Allahعَزَّوَجَلْ on top of them moved.
It is interesting to notice that the most controversial issues in Islam,
the issues that are attacked by the orientalist, the most,
happened to be issues that weren't instigated by Rasool Allah ﷺ but came directly from Allahعَزَّوَجَلْ.
The marriage of Rasool Ullah to Ayesha(عائشه) which is the marriage
that is attacked by the Kuffar(كفار), how can your prophet marry a girl, who's six years old.?
That was a marriage that wasn't initiated by Rasool Allah ﷺ.
Jibreel(جِبْرِيْل) came to Muhammadﷺ in a dream and this is in Bukhari(بخاريْ) and said:
هذه زوجك
This is your wife and he sees that dream for three consecutive nights,
Rasool Allah ﷺ said:
اني كن فيه خير بإذن الله
If there's any good in it, Allah will make it happen.
The execution of Banu Quraidha(بنوقريظه), all of them, this was the end of a tribe.
Just imagine a tribe was exterminated.
This was a command that came from Allahعَزَّوَجَلْ.
It pleased Allahعَزَّوَجَلْ, that command pleased Allahعَزَّوَجَلْ.
The marriage of Rasool Ullah to Zainab(زينب),
which is causing a lot of controversy also, in Orientalist circles.
This was a command of Allah.
فَلَمّا قَضىٰ زَيدٌ مِنها وَطَرًا زَوَّجناكَها
So you find that these issues are actually issues that are coming from Allahعَزَّوَجَلْ directly
therefore, when we are debating or discussing with the non believers,
we should not try to prove to them the validity of each and every point in Islam.
The issue is not that,
the issue is not whether you agree with the marriage of Rasool Allah ﷺ to Ayesha(عائشه) or not.
The issue is not whether you agree with what Rasool Allah ﷺ did to Banu Quraidha(بنوقريظه) or not.
The issue is, do you accept that Qur'an is the word of Allah or not,
do you accept that Muhammadﷺ is the messenger of Allah or not,
if you do accept that everything else will fall in place.
We don't have to argue about the details anymore,
because if you agree that Qur'an is the word of Allah and Muhammadﷺ is the Messenger of Allah,
you're going to accept everything that they do.
So let's not waste our time discussing these side issues,
because there's an endless number of them.
And let's focus on the prime issues and that is that Qur'an is the book of Allah.
They are only choosing these issues, not because it is causing them to stay away from Islam.
It is because they feel that these are the best vehicles to attack the religion.
It's not that if you convince them about it, they're going to become Muslim, that's not the case.
They have a more critical problem and that is they disagree
with Qur'an being the word of Allah and they disagree with Muhammadﷺ being the Messenger of Allah.
So these are the issues that need to be discussed.
I was reading a book by one Talib-e-Ilm(طالب علم) from Falastine(فلسطين), and student of knowledge.
It's called the path towards Jerusalem and he mentioned in it a strange Fatwa(فتوى),
it was kind of funny when I read it.
He said that killing the Jews Sunnah Muakida(سنة معكدة).
How would one derive such a Hukum(حكم) in a market,
but he got it from the Ghazwa(غزوة) Banu Quraidha(بنوقريظه).
He said that in all of the battles of Rasool Allah ﷺ, all of the battles.
If you look at the number of Jews that Rasool Allah ﷺ killed,
they are more than the combined number of the casualties of every other Ghazwa(غزوة) of Rasool Ullah.
In Banu Quraidha(بنوقريظه) alone 900.
And that is that tops that is more than the combined number of casualties
in all of the Ghazawat(غزوات) and Sarayah(سراية) of Rasool Allah ﷺ combined,
Allah Ho Alam(ألله أعلم), but again I would disagree with make turning it into a Hukum(حكم)
saying its Sunnah Muakida(سنة معكدة) or Fardh Kifaya(فرض كفاية), Fardh ain(فرض عين).
This is part of Jihad(جهاد) Fee-Sabeel-Lillah(فِي سَبيل الله), you don't make a Hukum(حكم) on it.
19) Banu Lahyan(بنولحيان).
It occurred on Rabi-Ul-Awwal(ربيع الأول) sixth year of Hijrah(هجرة).
Banu Lahyan(بنولحيان) are the ones, who killed the 70 scholars of Qur'an, who were sent to teach them.
Rasool Allah ﷺ went to take revenge for them,
Banu Lahyan(بنولحيان) ran away so no fighting occurred.
Number 20, Zuo Qird(ذوقرد) it occurred in sixth year of Hijrah(هجرة).
According to Ibn Is'haqq(اِبْنِ اِسْحَاقْ).
However Bukhari(بخاريْ) and Muslim(ألمسلم) state, it occurred in the beginning of the seventh year of Hijrah(هجرة),
and this is the Ghazwa(غزوة) that occurred because of the single man army of Salamah(سلمة),
we already read the story of Salamah Bin Akwah(سلمة بن الأكوع).
I'm the son of Al-Akwah(أكوع), today is the day of defeat for the mean.
Take it and I'm the son of Akwah(أكوع).
They say: Are you the Akwah(أكوع), who is following us since morning.?
Are you the Akwah(أكوع) following us on the morning and then he dies, those were his last words.
24) The opening of Makkah.
It occurred in Ramadan(رمضان), the eighth year of Hijrah(هجرة).
Rasool Allah ﷺ entered Makkah with an army of 12,000.
Ibn Nuhas(إبن نُحاس) in terms of his numbers.
It's actually 10,000 not 12,000.
I wonder if his book says 12,000 Or maybe, I made a mistake, but it's actually 10,000 not 12.
Even mentioned in the Bible about these 10,000.
And he enters with 10,000 saints,
10,000 saints!
These are the Sahabah(صحابه), who entered with him in Makkah.
On that day, he announced clemency for the people of Quraish(قُرَيْشْ), who had fought him for over 20 years.
I didn't mention it.
Oh we missed  Banu Mustalaq(بنومصطلق) Hudaybiyyah(حديبية) and Khaybar(خيبر)
21) Banu Mustalaq(بنومصطلق),
Ibn Is'haqq(اِبْنِ اِسْحَاقْ) claims that it occurred in the sixth year of Hijrah(هجرة),
the head of the tribe Al-Haris Bin Abi Zurar(ألحارث بن أبي ضرار) was forming an army to fight the Muslims.
Rasool Allah ﷺ attacked them.
They lived on the coast of the Red Sea.
They exchanged arrows for a while before the Muslims charged and defeated them.
Some were killed while others were taken as prisoners
and the Muslims won a large booty of sheep and camels.
Rasool Allah ﷺ married Javeriyah(جويرية), the daughter of their leader, Al-Haris(ألحارث).
22) Al-Hudaybiyya(ألحديبية),
It was in Zul Qaidah(ذولقعدة), six of Hijrah(هجرة).
Rasool Allah ﷺ headed for Umrah(عمرة) with 1400 of his Sahabah(صحابه).
These 1400 are very special because Allahعَزَّوَجَلْ revealed an Ayah(آية) about them.
So they went out with no intention of fighting,
however, the people of Quraish(قُرَيْشْ) refused to allow them access to Makkah.
He sent to them Uthman Ibn Affan(عثمان ابن عفان) to negotiate with them,
a false rumor reached the Messenger of Allah that Uthman(عثمان) was killed.
Rasool Ullah went out with the intention of Umrah(عمرة).
So they went in Ahraam(أحرام) and they went with the Al-Hadie(ألهدي), sheep.
They get there Quraish(قُرَيْشْ) say: No way we're going to allow them in,
they refused to allow the Muslims access.
So, Rasool Ullah is negotiating with them.
He told Umar(عُمَر) to go to Makkah.
Umar(عُمَر) said: O Rasool Ullah,
there is none of Banu Udae(بنوعدئي) left in Makkah to protect me.
So why don't you send Uthman(عثمان), because his family are strong in Makkah.
Uthman(عثمان) is from Bannu Umayyah(بَنُواُمَيَّة), and this is a strong family in Quraish(قُرَيْشْ).
So Uthman(عثمان) goes to Makkah.
But he was delayed in coming back.
So rumors spread that he was actually killed,
rumor spread that Uthman Ibn Affan(عثمان ابن عفان) was killed.
Rasool Allah ﷺ sits under a tree, under a cedar tree.
And he takes the pledge of allegiance from these 1400.
What was the Pledge of Allegiance.?
To die!
That was,
تبعنا على الموت
To pledge to die.
Uthman Ibn Affan(عثمان ابن عفان) because he was in Makkah, he wasn't present.
So, for example, the shia(شيعة) they say,
Uthman(عثمان) wasn't there at Badr(بدر), Uthman(عثمان) wasn't there at Baiyah(بَيْعة).
Where was he?
When it comes to Badr(بدر), Uthman Ibn Affan(عثمان ابن عفان) was ordered, by Rasool Allah ﷺ to stay behind,
because his wife Ruqaiyah(رقية), the daughter of Rasool Allah ﷺ was ill.
So Rasool Ullah told them to stay behind,
but Uthman(عثمان) is counted as one of Al-Badrieen(ألبدريين),
he's counted as one of the ones, who attended Badr(بدر)
because he received the share in the booty of Badr(بدر).
In Baiyah Ar-Ridwan(بَيْعة الرضوان), he wasn't there
because the whole purpose of the Baiyah(بَيْعة) was for him.
So Rasool Allah ﷺ because Uthman(عثمان) wasn't present,
Rasool Allah ﷺ put his hands together and said:
And this pledges is for Uthman(عثمان).
So Rasool Allah ﷺ represented Uthman(عثمان) in his pledge.
It's much better than Uthman(عثمان) doing it for himself.
The Ayah(آية)0 that was revealed,
لَقَد رَضِيَ اللَّهُ عَنِ المُؤمِنينَ إِذ يُبايِعونَكَ تَحتَ الشَّجَرَةِ
Allah is pleased with the believers,
who give you the Pledge of Allegiance under the tree, 1400.
These are the ones, whom Allah witnessed declared that He is pleased with.
Eventually After long negotiations, a truce was signed, between Rasool Allah ﷺ and Quraish(قُرَيْشْ).
The one who represented the people of Quraish(قُرَيْشْ) in the negotiations
was Sohail Bin Amr(سهيل بن عمرو).
And you know the terms of the agreement of Hudaybiyah(حديبية) that they stop fighting.
And whoever comes from Makkah to Madina is returned
and whoever goes from Madina to Makkah is not returned.
Whoever enters into the alliance of Muhammad(محمد) is accepted
and whoever enters into the alliance of Quraish(قُرَيْشْ) is also accepted,
when they were writing the terms of the agreement,
Rasool Allah ﷺ is spelling out the terms and Ali(علي) is writing.
And Sohail Bin Amr(سهيل بن عمرو) is representing Quraish(قُرَيْشْ).
So Rasool Allah ﷺ told Ali(علي) to write.
He said:
بسم الله الرحمن الرحيم
Sohail(سهيل) said: Stop! We don't know,
who Ar-Rahman(ألرحمن) Ar-Rahim(الرحيم) is. Write!
بسمك اللهم
In the name of Allah we don't know Ar-Rahman(ألرحمن) Ar-Rahim(الرحيم).
So Rasool Allah ﷺ told Ali(علي) to change it.
And then he told Ali(علي) to write,
هذا ما صالح عليه محمد رسول الله ، سهيل ابن عمرو
This is an agreement between Muhammad(محمد), the Messenger of Allah,
and Sohail Ibn Amr(سهيل إبن عمرو).
Sohail(سهيل) said:
If we agree that you're the Messenger of Allah, we wouldn't be negotiating with you, in the first place.
So he said: Change it and write your name and the name of your father.
So Rasool Ullah told Ali(علي) to erase it, Ali(علي) refused.
So Rasool Allah ﷺ said: Show it to me, and Rasool Ullah wiped it with his hand.
So, that was Sulh Al-Hudaybiyah(صلح الحديبية).
Negotiations took time because the people of Quraish(قُرَيْشْ) were sending one after another,
to negotiate with Rasool Ullah.
One of them in whom they sent was Urwa Bin Masood As-Saqafi(عروة بن مسعود ألثقفي).
They sent him to negotiate with Rasool Allah ﷺ.
And they didn't reach an agreement.
Abu Bakr(ابوبكر) said: People are short sighted.
They didn't realize the wisdom behind Sulh Al-Hudaybiyah(صلح الحديبية).
Because you know Umar(عُمَر), was not happy with the terms.
He said: Why don't we fight them.
Abu Bakr(ابوبكر) said: This is the messenger of Allah and he knows better.
So Abu Bakr(ابوبكر) is commenting on this a while later,
he's saying people are short sighted.
They don't see the wisdom behind Sulh Al-Hudaybiyah(صلح الحديبية).
Allah has His Qadar(قَدَر) and His Qadar(قَدَر) takes its time.
But the people hasten things.
He said: I've seen Urwa Bin Masood As-Saqafi(عروة بن مسعود ألثقفي) one year later,
when Rasool Allah ﷺ made Hajj(حَجْ).
He said: I saw Urwa Bin Masood(عروة بن مسعود).
When Rasool Allah ﷺ was shaving his head.
I saw Urwa Bin Masood(عروة بن مسعود) going down on his knees,
picking up the clippings of Rasool Allah ﷺ and putting them on his eyes,
to get the blessing from Rasool Allah ﷺ, after one year.
Urwa Bin Masood As-Saqafi(عروة بن مسعود ألثقفي) who was negotiating with Rasool Allah ﷺ
and did not reach an agreement with him.
After one year he is going down on his knees to get the blessing of the hair of Rasool Allah ﷺ.
Al-Hudaybiyah(حديبية) was one of the greatest openings in Islam.
Khaybar(خَيْبَر) N0. 23.
This was the last Jewish community in the Arabian Peninsula,
after the return of Rasool Allah ﷺ from Hudaybiyah(حديبية).
He stayed in Madina, Dhul Hijjah(ذوالحجة) and part of Muharram(محرم).
And then marched towards the last community of Jews living in Hijaz(حجاز), Khaybar(خَيْبَر).
Khaybar(خَيْبَر) was made of a few strong fortresses.
When the Muslims arrived there, the Jewish king Marhab(مرحب) came out, asking for a duel.
Amr Bin Akwah(عمرو بن أكوع) brother of Salamah Bin Akwah(سلمة بن الأكوع)
went out to face him. Marhab(مرحب) struck Amr(عمرو) and his sword got stuck in Amr(عمرو)'s shield,
in the same time Amr(عمرو) hit himself with his own sword and died.
Amr(عمرو) had a short sword.
So when he went to stab Marhab(مرحب).
It came back and we hit him on the kneecap.
And he ended up killing himself.
Now, Salamah(سلمة), his brother heard some of the Sahabah(صحابه)
saying that Amr(عمرو) has lost all of his deeds, he killed himself.
So he went to the Messenger of Allah crying, and he said:
Did my brother lose all of his deeds?
Rasool Allah ﷺ said: Who said that?
He said: Some of your companions.
Rasool Allah ﷺ said: No! They are wrong.
Your brother gets double the reward.
Now after Marhab(مرحب) killed Amir(عامر), he asked for another challenge.
Rasool Allah ﷺ said: Who would go out to this man,
Muhammad Ibn Maslima(محمد إبن مسلمة) said: I would.!
I am the angry Avenger, Marhab(مرحب) killed my brother yesterday.
Aamir(عامر) was his relative.
The Messenger of Allah said: Then go! May Allah help you against him.
When Muhammad(محمد), met with Marhab(مرحب) a tree came in their way.
So now, Marhab(مرحب), and Muhammad Ibn Maslima(محمد إبن مسلمة) are revolving around this tree.
And every time they would hit, try to make a strike, it would hit the tree.
So Ibn Nuhas(إبن نُحاس) says:
When Muhammad(محمد) met with Marhab(مرحب) a tree came in their way,
and each one of them would use it to seek protection from the other strike.
And with every strike some of its branches and leaves would be cut,
until none of them were left.
You know they're fighting around this tree and revolving,
and they're cutting down the branches until all what you're left with, is trunk.
Then Marhab(مرحب) charged, and struck him with his sword,
Muhammad(محمد) shielded himself and Marhab(مرحب) sword was stuck in the shield,
and he failed to pull it out, Muhammad(محمد) took advantage of that
and cut off both his legs and left him.
Marhab(مرحب) begged the Muhammad(محمد) to kill him, but Muhammad(محمد) refused,
he said: I won't, I want you to taste death like my brother did yesterday, and he walked away.
Later on, Ali(علي) passed by Marhab(مرحب) and finished him off.
When Marhab(مرحب) was killed his brother Yaser(ياسر) asked for a duel
Az-Zubair Bin Awwam(ألزبير بن عوام) wents to face him.
Safiyah(صفية), Az-Zubair(ألزبير)'s mother and the aunt of Rasool Allah ﷺ said: My son would be killed.
سيقتل بي
Because Yaser(ياسر) and Marhab(مرحب) were well known.
So, Safiyah(صفية) said: He's going to kill my son.
Rasool Allah ﷺ said: In Sha Allah(إنْ شاءالله), your son will kill him, and he did.
Rasool Allah ﷺ opened Khaybar(خَيْبَر),
their fighting men were killed, their women and children enslaved, and their wealth was appropriated.
24) The opening of Makkah.
it occurred in Ramadan(رمضان) the eighth year of Hijrah(هجرة),
Rasool Allah ﷺ entered Makkah with an army of 10,000 with no fighting, except for a few skirmishes.
And it was a day of forgiveness.
On that day, he announced clemency for the people of Quraish(قُرَيْشْ),
who had fought him for over 20 years.
25) Hunain(حنين)
it occurred immediately after the opening of Makkah.
The leader of how Hawazin(هوازن) Malik Bin Auf(مالك بن عوف) assembled a huge army from Hawazin(هوازن),
Thaqeef(ثقيف), Nadhr(نذر), Jasm(جثم) and Saad Bin Bakr(سعد بن بكر).
Rasool Allah ﷺ went out to fight them.
When the Muslims were passing through the valley of Hunain(حنين), they were ambushed by the enemy.
The entire Muslim army went into disarray.
And they fled, with the exception of a small number of Sahabah(صحابه), who surrounded the Messenger of Allah.
They started out an army of 12,000.
10,000, who opened Makkah 2000 new Muslims from Makkah.
So the total number was 12,000, that's when they were very impressed with their numbers,
they said:
لن نغلب اليوم على قلة
We're not going to lose because of lack of numbers.
These 12,000 ran away in front of the army of Hawazin(هوازن)
the only ones, who stood behind are Rasool Allah ﷺ with 80 of his Sahabah(صحابه).
And this army of 80, is the army that defeated Hawazin(هوازن).
It's not the 12,000 it's 80.
And not all of them were old muslims, Al-Abbas(العباس) was a new Muslim.
If we're going to consider him to be new, but he might have been Muslim in Makkah for some time.
Rasool Allah ﷺ told his Uncle Al-Abbas(العباس), who had a loud voice to call Al-Ansaar(اَلْاَنْصَار),
they came from every direction, and fought furiously.
After a short while the enemy was defeated,
the booty was 24,000 camels, 40,000 sheep, and a large amount of silver.
26) At-Taef(اَلطَّائِف), it was during Shawal(شوال) the eighth year of Hijrah(هجرة),
after the defeat of Thaqeef(ثقيف), during the Battle of Hunain(حنين),
they went back to their town, At-Taef(اَلطَّائِف) and closed its gates.
Rasool Allah ﷺ followed them and camped close by,
laying a severe siege on them.
The people of Thaqeef(ثقيف) attacked the Muslims with a shower of arrows.
When it became apparent that the Thaqeef(ثقيف) won't fall easily.
Rasool Allah ﷺ sought counsel from his Sahabah(صحابه).
Nofal(نوفل) said: Thaqeef(ثقيف) are like a fox in the hole.
If you stay at it, you will get it and if you leave it, it won't harm you.
So Rasool Allah ﷺ decided to leave.
And that's shower of arrows, one of those arrows hit Abdullah Bin Abi Bakr(عبدالله بن أبي بكر).
It didn't kill him instantaneously, he only died when his father was Khalifah(خليفه).
When the delegation of At-Taef(اَلطَّائِف), who were already Muslim, came to meet the Khalifah(خليفه), Abu Bakr(ابوبكر).
Abu Bakr(ابوبكر) pulled out that arrow, the arrow that killed his son Abdullah(عبدالله).
And he showed it to the delegation.
He said: Does anybody know who this arrow belongs to.?
So one of them held the arrow and said this arrow belongs to me.
I sharpened it, and I'm the one who fired it.
Abu Bakr(ابوبكر) said: That is the arrow that killed my son.
So the man said: Al-hamdulillah(ألحمدلله), who gave your son martyrdom through me,
and Al-hamdulillah(ألحمدلله) who guided me after that, to Islam.
Number 27) Tabook(تبوك)
It occurred in Rajab(رجب) ninth of Hijrah(هجرة).
This was the last army Rasool Allah ﷺ participates in.
The Messenger of Allah, marched into Roman territory,
when he heard that they are gathering an army to attack Madina.
The Muslims made their move in a very difficult time.
It was a year of drought, poverty.
It was right before the time of harvest and it was during hot season,
the hypocrites stayed behind and their hypocrisy was exposed in Surah At-Toba(سورة التوبة).
The Muslims assembled an army of 30,000, strong,
the largest army ever assembled by the Messenger of Allah.
Due to poverty some Sahabah(صحابه) came to the Messenger of Allah,
urging him to supply them in order for them to join the army.
When he told them that he has no finances for them.
They left with tears flowing from their eyes, for not being able to join the army.
The Roman emperor was stationed in Hims(حمص) at the time in order to prepare for war.
He assembled an army of Romans and Christian Arabs.
When they heard of the Muslim army they decided not to fight.
Rasool Allah ﷺ waited in Tabook(تبوك) for 10 days when the Romans did not show up,
he returned to Madina.
After he established his presence in the lower parts of Ash-Sham(ألشَّام)
and Northern Arabia.
If you look at the number of battles that Rasool Allah ﷺ fought
and divide them by the years he spent in Madina.
It comes out to about two to three battles, a year.
That's a lot!
Tayeb(طيِّب) In Sha Allah(إنْ شاءالله), we'll end with that,
and next week we'll start talking about the Sarayah(سراية),
talk about the Sarayah(سراية).
Questions, otherwise we'll take tea break.
Question From Audience:
It's happened in Harub(حروب) of Ar-Riddah(ردَّة) the Muslims,
this was with Al-Alaa Bin Hadhrami(ألأعلى بن حزرمي),
Al-Alaa Bin Hadhrami(ألأعلى بن حزرمي) was one of the Owliyaa(أولياء) of Allah.
Many Karamaat(كرامات) happened with him.
He was in the time of Abu Bakr(ابوبكر).
He is the one, who walked over water.
And he is the one, who may Dua(دُعَا), when their camel were lost,
and the camels just came, peacefully back.
And when they were in the land that had many scorpions and spiders and snakes.
He made an announcement he said:
We are the messengers of the Messenger of Allah and they all left.
He was a man of Karamat(کرامات),
Al-Alaa Bin Hadhrami(ألأعلى بن حزرمي), he camped next to the enemy.
So at night he was hearing these loud voices,
he told one of his men to go and spy on them,
he said: They're drunk.
He said: Lets make our move.
They attacked at night.
So, one of their leaders, he ran out of his tent,
and he jumped over his horse, but the stirrup of the horse,
where you put your feet.
It fell down or something or it broke.
So he said:
من يصلح لي رقابي
Who will fix it for me.
So one of the Muslims, who was next to him.
He said: I will fix it for you.
He said: Lift up your leg, lift your leg,
so that he could fix it.
Lift you leg! So he lifted his leg, he chopped off, he cut off his leg.
He said: I could hear the sound of the sword on the bone.
So the man fell off his horse.
So he told the Muslim to come and kill him.
He said: I'm gonna leave you, the way you are.
And whenever one of the Muslims soldier will pass next to him.
He would say: Please kill me! Please kill me!
And they would all leave him.
Until one of the Muslims passed next to him,
he said: Please kill me!
He said: Alright! Fine,
I'll kill you.
He killed him.
And then he said:
When I saw his leg laying next to him,
I regretted that I killed him.
He didn't know that he was bleeding.
So, this does happen, in battle.
But see with the sharpening the sword.
That's for execution.
The execution is different executions should be done in the most compassionate way
unless, again, these specific people need to be brutally killed.
But in battle that's different.